Guide to the Group Against Smog and Pollution (GASP) Records, 1968-2002 AIS.1979.21
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Outreach, 1968-1993; IV.
  - Correspondence, Policy and Announcements about Public Participation and Toxins, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Environmental Information Center Proposal, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Environmental Protection Agency Grant Materials, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Emission Reduction Technology Program Records, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Earth Summit Photographs, Certificate and Meeting Announcement, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Proposed Supplemental Environmental Projects, 1999-2001 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Citizens Helping our Community (CHOC) Membership Lists and Correspondence, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Subject Files, 1970-1996; V.
  The Subject Files series includes information that is of such a wide variety of environmental causes they could not be easily arranged into the other series in the collection. Subjects include energy, water, air pollution, transportation, acid rain and hazardous waste materials. Newspaper clippings, conference records, photographs, policies, correspondence, meeting transcripts, testimonies and news releases comprise this series. It is arranged chronologically between 1970 and 1996.
  - Correspondence with Politicians Ahapp, Milton and Thornburgh, 1969-1978 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Photographs and Postcards of Pollution in Pennsylvania, ca. 1970s (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Photographs and Slides of Pollution in Pittsburgh and Braddock, 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Environmental Law Violations Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Educational Programming Correspondence and Children's School Reports and Correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence about Energy Issues, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Duquesne Light Utilities and Energy Records, 1971-1981 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Emissions Correspondence and Fact Sheets, 1971-1982 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Drinking Water Quality Correspondence and Newspaper Clippings, 1971-1983 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, Testimony and News Releases about Energy Issues, 1973-1982 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Energy Regulations and Meeting Announcements, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Air Pollution Monitoring Records, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Regional Rail Reorganization Act Correspondence, Memo and Testimony, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Pennsylvania Lung Association Correspondence, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Ground Water Statements and Legislation, 1975-1983 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Air Pollution Newspaper Clippings, 1975-1996 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Allegheny County Health Department Bureau of Air Pollution Control Emergency Plan, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - President Carter's Energy Plan Correspondence, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Press Releases and Correspondence about Air Pollution, 1977-1981 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - I-279 Construction Correspondence, 1977-1983 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Testimony, Advertisements and Correspondence about Transportation Issues, 1977-1993 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Action Seminar on Acid Rain Records, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Acid Rain Correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Acid Rain Testimony and Press Releases, 1979-1983 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Allegheny County Industrial Hazardous Waste Records, 1979-1983 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Acid Rain Newspaper Clippings, 1979-1983 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Hazardous Waste Testimony, Correspondence and Newspaper Clippings, 1979-1990 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Waste Alert Conference Records, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Allegheny County Industrial and Hazardous Waste Management Plan Report, July 22, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Industrial and Hazardous Advisory Group Correspondence, Reports and Meeting Transcript, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Newsclippings and Photographs Documenting Fire Damage of the Eastminster Church, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Reports on Acid Rain in Pennsylvania, 1980-1982 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Acid Rain Network Correspondence, Newsletters and Data, 1980-1982 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Acid Rain Task Force Reports and Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Pennsylvania Energy Policy Correspondence and Testimony, 1980-1983 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Background Information on Acid Rain, 1980-1984 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Solid Waste Management Plan Testimony, 1980-1990 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Citizen's Hazardous Waste Involvement Program Records, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Analysis of Effluent Guidelines Limitations Standards for Iron and Steel Manufacturers, April 1981 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Citizen's Hazardous Waste Roundtable Meeting Minutes, Progress Report and Remarks, 1981-1983 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Acid Rain Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Federal Clean Water Act Correspondence, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Acid Deposition Report, April 1984 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Citing Hazardous Waste Facilities Guide, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Municipal Waste Planning and Resource Recovery Act Statements and Correspondence, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Pennsylvania Acid Rain Coalition By-laws and Correspondence, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Acid Rain Bills and Correspondence, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Gasoline Volatility Regulations Correspondence, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Alleghany County Sanitary Authority Correspondence, Testimony and Fact Sheet, 1990-1992 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Duquesne Light Transmission Line Records, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Photographs of Pollution in Pennsylvania, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Photographs of Pollution and Testimonies, undated (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Radio spot "Let's Clear the Air", undated (Box 10, Folder 44)
- Related Companies, 1971-1976; VI.
  The Related Companies series contains correspondence, legal materials, and other documents relating to Air Pollution Variance Petition Files between 1971-1976. The folders are organized alphabetically according to the organization responsible for filing the petition. In addition to the written documents, the series contains diagrams, schematic plans and study data for various industrial operations. These were run by various companies, including: Pittsburgh Plate Glass, US Steel, Edgar Thomson, Jones Laughlin, and the Allegheny Power Service Corporation. The flat file contains three copies of the "Dirty Gertie Award", two blank, and one given to US Steel for its "contribution to air pollution in Allegheny County".
  - Abrasive Materials, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Alcoa, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Alcosan, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Allegheny Contracting, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Allegheny County Housing Authority, 1973-1975 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Allegheny County Steam Heating, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Allegheny Label, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Allegheny Ludlum Steel, 1973-1975 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - American Oil, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - American Tallow, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Armour and Company, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Armstrong and Cork Company, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Ashland Oil Company, 1973-1975 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Atlantic Richfield (ARCO), 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Balch Flavor, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Bethlehem Steel, 1972-1975 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Blawnox Foundry and Mill Machinery, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 17-18)
  - Brass and Bronze Casting Company, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Burrell Construction Company, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Calgon Corporation, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Carlynton School District, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Carnegie-Mellon University, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Carnegie Tar and Asphalt Company, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Clairton School District, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Codo Manufacturing Company, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Combustion Engineering, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Dixmont State Hospital, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Duquesne Light, Cheswick Power Station, 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Duquesne Light, Phillips Power Station, 1972-1976 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Duquesne Light, Beaver Valley Power Station (Nuclear Plant), 1971-1976 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Duquesne Light, James Reed Power Station, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Duquesne Light, Colfax Power Station; 12th Street Heating, 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Duquesne Light, Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Duquesne Slag, 1971-1975 (Box 11, Folder 35-36)
  - Edgewater Corporation, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Elizabeth Forward School District, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Exxon, 1973-1975 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - General Electric, 1972-1975 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Gulf Oil Corporation, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Hafner Coffee Company, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Hanlon Gregory Galvanizing, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - H.J. Heinz Company, 1972-1976 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - O. Hommel Company, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Inland Products, 1971-1975 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - J. & L., 1972-1975 (Box 11, Folder 47-48)
  - J. & L., 1971-1975 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Keystone Casing Company, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Louis Hahn and Son, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Mackintosh-Hemphill, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Marquette Cement, 1972-1974 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - McKeesport Hospital, 1972-1974 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Mesta Machine, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Metallurgical Exoproducts, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Mobile Oil Company, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Neville Cement, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Neville Chemical Company, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - M. O'Herron Company, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Papercraft Corporation, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Perlite Manufacturing Company, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Phillips Petroleum Company, 1972-1974 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Pittsburgh Activated Carbon, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Pittsburgh Brewing Company, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Pittsburgh Coal Company, 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Pittsburgh Forging, 1972-1974 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Pittsburgh Metal Lithographing, 1971-1974 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Pittsburgh Pacific Processing Company, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Pittsburgh Plate Glass (PPG), 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Pittsburgh School District, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Robroy Industries, 1972-1974 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Russell Industries, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Satellite Alloy, 1971-1974 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Shenango, 1971-1975 (Box 12, Folder 28-29)
  - SOHIO Petroleum Company, 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Southwest Grease and Oil, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Spang and Company, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Sto Rox School District, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - St. John's Hospital, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Sulfuric Acid Plant, Neville Island (U.S. Steel), 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Sun Oil Company, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Texaco, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Union Steel Castings, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - United States Gypsum Company, 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Universal Cyclops, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - U.S. Steel, General, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - U.S. Steel, Boys Shop, 1971-1974 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - U.S. Steel, Clairton Works, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - U.S. Steel, Irvin Works, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - U.S. Steel, Sinter Plant, Homestead, 1972-1975 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - U.S. Steel, Slag Quenching, 1971-1974 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Steel Stainless Steel Scarfing (Homestead Works), 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Vulcan Materials, 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Westinghouse Electric Corporation, 1972-1975 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - West Mifflin, Borough of, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - West Penn Power, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
  - Woodville State Hospital, 1972-1976 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Dirty Gertie Awards (Map-case 4, Drawer 10)